We're going to critique some videos I
haven't had a look yet.
Let's get into the content.
How many calories do you need to burn in
your workout for it to be effective?
Zero. Yeah, that's right,
because the aim of your workout shouldn't
even be-
First concern is audio.
Let's start this again.
A little bit echoey.
I'm wondering where the mic is.
-your workout for it to be effective.
How many calories do you need to burn in
your workout for it to be effective? Hook.
Zero. Yeah.
Zero. What you've done is here,
you paid off straight away the question.
We want to take people maybe on a bit more
of an emotional journey before
paying them off.
How many calories do we need to burn in a
workout for it to be
effective?
Is there a certain amount of time we
should be training for, and do we
need to be training at a certain intensity
for that fat loss to be maximized?
But before we get into that,
let's understand one important concept
about fat
loss.
We do not go to the gym to burn calories
to lose fat.
We go to the gym to get stronger. In fact,
fat loss doesn't even occur in the gym.
It happens outside.
So to get back to the first question,
the answer technically
would be zero.
Think about any kind of story.
"Top Gear," "The Grand Tour," rest in
peace.
We're going to go from one side of Africa
to the other.
It's not like, "And
is it possible to drive across Africa
in a 30-year-old car? Yes,
we completed it.
Let's start the video."
When you look at your total daily energy
expenditure, you'll see that-
Don't hate this. There
is a lot of videos online.
I've even done ones.
We're talking about thermic effects of
feeding. Love that you got the chart.
Love the colors being used.
I feel like we've missed the opportunity
to have a
physical prop,
have something in front of us
that we could use.
We could have used 20 kg bumper plates to
represent BMR, basal metabolic rate.
We could have used a 15-kilogram plate to
represent NEAT, a nice little yellow
plate.
We could have used a green plate to
represent thermic effects of feeding,
and then for EAT,
exercise activity thermogenesis,
we could use the five-kilogram
plate.
The workouts only account for about 5% to
10% of your daily
expenditure.
Then we could have held
that 10-kilogram plate and gone,
although this is a lot,
compared to all the rest of the weights
here, it's not that much.
Focus on building strength and building-
Great use of B-roll. Tiago,
I know you're relatively new to the
content game, and
I'm going to say it, this,
even heavily critiqued by myself with a
lot of
holes to pick in it, is still really good.
It's still way better than any of my
content I put out for years in the
beginning.
Don't pay off the hook so quick.
Use a prop.
If you're using visuals in your video,
you're using them because you want to
portray your point in a way that
if the person watching can see something,
they can
understand better.
If seeing something makes them understand
better, let's think,
let's look around the house.
Let's use props.
If you're really stuck for ideas,
you can always go into ChatGPT, say,
"This is the
concept I'm trying to get across.
Help me think of some ideas."